attonlineoffers.com 2009-09-21

# Privacy Policy

Cingular is now part of the new AT&T. As we continue to consolidate and re-brand the company from Cingular to AT&T, we will be updating our privacy policies to reflect this change. For now, however, the Cingular privacy policy continues to apply to your wireless services provided by AT&T and your interactions with our wireless Web site pages.

Cingular Wireless uses email, short text messages, telemarketing, and direct mail to inform you about products or services we think will interest you. If you do not wish to receive these types of communications, learn how you can opt out.

(Effective date: October 21, 2006)

Cingular Wireless has a long-standing policy of protecting customer privacy.

We believe that you should know what information we collect from you, as well as how that information is used, disclosed, and protected. We have created this policy statement (the "Policy") to explain our privacy practices and policies.

We will not sell or disclose your personal information to unaffiliated third parties without your consent except as otherwise provided in this Policy. We may use information about who you are, where and when you browse on the Web, where your wireless device is located, and how you use our network to provide you better service and enrich your user experience when you sign up or use any of our products or services.

Cingular Wireless may make available shorter or machine-readable versions of this Privacy Policy. These additional policies are intended only as summaries of this complete Privacy Policy. This Policy applies to customers who purchase and use our services and products in the United States. Collection, use, disclosure, and protection of personal information may be subject to different regulation outside the United States.

Cingular Wireless will revise and update this Policy as it deems appropriate, including, for example, if our practices change or if changes in the law so require. You should refer back to this page for the latest information.

CINGULAR WIRELESS PRIVACY POLICY

We have created the Cingular Wireless Privacy Policy (the "Policy") to explain our privacy practices. When you use any Cingular Wireless product or service, you should understand when and how personal information is collected, used, disclosed and protected.

We will not sell or disclose information to unaffiliated third parties without your consent except as otherwise provided in this Policy. We may use information about who you are, where and when you browse on the Web, where your wireless device is located, and how you use our network to provide you better service and enrich your user experience when you sign up or use any of our products or services.

Cingular Wireless will revise and update this Policy if our practices change or if changes in the law so require.

Information Collected About You

We collect a variety of personal information about users of our products or services. Personal information is information that can be directly associated with a specific person or entity, such as a name, address, telephone number, email address, or information about activities directly linked to that person.

Our definition of personal information does not include "aggregate" information. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of services or customers from which individual customer identities have been removed. For example, we could prepare a report that indicates that a certain number of our customers always use their wireless phones at a certain time of day at a specific location. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and customer needs so that we can better consider new services or tailor existing services to customer desires. The aggregate data also might be purchased by or shared with a third party, for example, one interested in locating a business in a particular part of town.

Here are the types of personal and other information we collect. You should refer to the rest of this Policy to see how we use, disclose, and protect that information:

Information You Give Us We collect information you give us when you purchase a Cingular Wireless product or use services. For example, you may provide us a billing address and credit information, including your social security number or business identifier, when signing up for service or perhaps purchasing a product through our online store. You might not have thought about it this way, but the numbers dialed from your wireless phone to make a call are an example of information you give us and that we collect and use so we can bill you appropriately and investigate fraudulent usage.

Automatically Collected Information We automatically receive certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, when you visit a Cingular Wireless Web site, our systems automatically collect your IP address and the type of browser you use. When you browse the wireless web, our systems log the Web sites you visit. Similarly, all wireless communications systems know when your phone is turned on and approximately where the device is physically located—that's how calls or messages are delivered to you in real time.

Information from Other Sources We may obtain information about you from outside sources and add it to or combine it with your account information. For example, we may receive credit information for purposes of initiating service. We also may use commercially available demographic and marketing information from third parties to help us better serve you or inform you about products or services that we think will be of interest to you. We sometimes receive updated delivery and address information from our shippers or other sources so that we can correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily. And, we often receive information from the dealer from whom you purchase your wireless phone or device prior to initiating service with us.

We also may purchase email lists from third parties for advertising purposes. We only purchase lists of individuals who have allowed third-party use of their email address for marketing purposes. If you have previously requested to participate in an email advertising program, the information we receive may include your name, information on previous transactions, or any other personal information you have provided.

Cingular Wireless recognizes that parents often purchase our products and services for family use, including for use by minors. Any information collected from such usage will appear to be the personal information of the actual subscriber to the service, and will be treated as such under this Policy. If we make available offers and products online where a child informs us that he or she is under the age of 13, we will ask a parent to confirm his/her consent in advance of further collection, use or disclosure of personal information from that child. 

In a Business Agreement, our customer is a business or other entity purchasing service for employees or other authorized users. If you receive certain benefits through a business or government customer's agreement with us, this Policy will generally govern your personal information. However, if you receive service where a business or government entity pays Cingular for your account or is otherwise liable to Cingular for the charges (for example, as a guarantor if you fail to pay), we may share your account information with that entity. If you receive certain benefits tied to a Business Agreement, but you are liable for your own charges, then we may share enough account information with that entity to verify your continuing eligibility for those benefits. Please contact Cingular if you have any questions about who is the liable party on your bill.

Children's Online Privacy Protection Act If we make available offers and products online where a child informs us that he or she is under the age of 13, we will ask a parent to confirm his/her consent in advance of further collection, use or disclosure of personal information from that child. You should be aware, however, that wireless devices and services purchased for family use may be used by minors without the knowledge of Cingular Wireless. If that happens, any information collected from the usage will appear to be the personal information of the actual adult subscriber and treated as such under this Policy.

Internal Use In general, we use personal information to serve our customers, to enhance and extend our customer relationship, and to enable our customers to take maximum advantage of products and services we think they would enjoy. For example, by understanding how you use our Web site, we are able to customize and personalize your experience. More specifically, we use personal information for billing purposes, to provide services or complete transactions you have requested, to anticipate and resolve problems with your services, and to create and inform you of products or services from Cingular Wireless or others that better meet your needs.

Cingular Wireless uses email, short text messages, telemarketing, and direct mail to inform you about products or services we think will interest you. You can modify your preferences on receiving these types of communications:

If you are currently a Cingular Wireless customer and wish to change your preferences on receiving these types of communications, you can do one of the following to tell us your preferences:

  * Complete an [online form](http://www.wireless.att.com/privacy/customer-opt-out.jsp).
  * Visit the ["My Profile"](https://www.wireless.att.com/olam/dashboardAction.olamexecute) page, if you manage your account online.
  * Call Customer Service at 1-800-331-0500.

If you are not a current customer of Cingular Wireless and wish to opt out of receiving marketing communications, you can complete an online form to tell us your preferences.

While you may choose not to receive marketing information from us, you will continue to receive invoices, customer service-related notifications, and other similar information from us electronically or otherwise.

Third-Party Use You should review the following section to understand when Cingular Wireless discloses personal information to third parties.

Disclosure of Personal Information Information about our customers is one of our most important business assets, and therefore we strive to protect it and keep it confidential. We do not sell personal information to third parties without your consent. When and what types of information Cingular Wireless discloses depends on the service and in some cases the choices you have made.

Cingular Wireless will not disclose personal information other than in accordance with this Policy. In general, that means that you must consent to the disclosure in advance. Depending on the service, we may obtain your consent in a number of ways, including:

  * In writing;
  * Verbally;
  * Online by clicking a button;
  * Through the use of a dialing string or button on a wireless device or handset; or
  * At the time of initiation of a particular service offering, when your consent is part of the required terms and conditions to use that service.

For example, your consent to disclose personal information can be implied simply by the nature of your request, such as when you ask us to deliver an email or short message to another person. Your return address is disclosed as part of the service and your consent to do so is implied by your use of the service. To determine how personal information may be disclosed as part of a particular service, you should review the terms and conditions of use for that service.

We share personal information with third parties as necessary to complete a transaction, perform a service on our behalf (such as enhancing our ability to serve you better), or perform a service that you have requested. When the third party acts solely on our behalf, Cingular Wireless does not allow them to use your information for other purposes. For example, our vendors process and print your billing statement on our behalf. They can only use the personal information we give them to produce the billing statement. When we write off an account for non-payment, Cingular Wireless sometimes discloses personal information about the account to third parties such as credit bureaus. Credit bureaus may use the personal information to update their records. Cingular Wireless does not currently disclose wireless numbers in AT&T listings or published directories. If we do so in the future, you will be able to choose whether your number is listed.

Aside from our services, however, you may also want to take advantage of services and products offered by other companies utilizing our wireless service. In those cases, you will be providing information to those companies, and information about you received by those third parties will be governed by their privacy policies, not this Policy. For example, if you are roaming on the network of another carrier, information about your usage and the numbers you dial will be available to the carrier providing the service. Also, as another example, if you purchase something using our mobile Internet service, you will be disclosing personal information directly to the company facilitating the transaction, a merchant bank and the merchant. Finally, if you bought your wireless device from a third party retailer or dealer, both they and Cingular Wireless will have personal information as a result of the transaction and your ongoing service with Cingular. Whenever third parties have a role in any such transaction, you should review their privacy policies as well.

From time to time you may be able to participate in contests, giveaways, or other similar promotions we sponsor. Except as explained otherwise in the rules for a particular contest, giveaway, or promotion, any personal information you provide will be used in accordance with this Policy.

In addition, from time to time you may be able to participate in our surveys to help us improve our offerings and services. Except as explained otherwise in the survey, any personal information so collected will be used for our internal purposes.

Under federal law, you have a right, and we have a duty, to protect the confidentiality of information about your telephone usage, the services you buy from us, who you call, and the location of your device on our network when you make a voice call. This information is sometimes referred to as "Customer Proprietary Network Information," or "CPNI." We share CPNI and other personal information about you with affiliates of AT&T and BellSouth Corporation (the parent companies of Cingular) that provide telecommunications services to which you also subscribe. Before sharing CPNI in any other way, we will first notify you of your rights under the law, describe how we intend to use the CPNI, and give you an opportunity to opt out of such usage (or, when required by law, to opt in).

Business Transfers: Information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider, as well as in the unlikely event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which personal information would be transferred as one of the business assets of the company.

Protection of Cingular Wireless and Others: We release personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law or in good faith reliance on legal process (e.g., court orders, subpoenas, E911 information, etc.); enforce or apply our customer agreements; initiate, render, bill, and collect for services; protect our rights or property, or protect users of those services and other carriers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, or subscription to, such services; facilitate or verify the appropriate calculation of taxes, fees, or other obligations due to a local, state, or federal government; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications, or justifies disclosure of records, to a governmental entity without delay.

Cingular Wireless Use of Cookies

Cookies are small files placed on your computer's hard drive by a Web site when you visit. These files identify your computer and record your preferences and other data about your visit so that when you return to the site, the site knows who you are and can personalize your visit. For example, cookies enable a Web site shopping cart to function so that you only have to check out once. Consequently, cookies are often tied to the use of personally identifiable information while using our site, and some functionality may be lost if you choose not to accept the use of cookies.

In general, we use cookies to collect information so that we can determine how to improve our site by seeing which areas, features and products are most popular; to personalize the site and make recommendations based on products you have liked in the past as well as to improve the site experience; and to complete transactions you have requested. Advertisers that serve ads on our site may also use their own cookies. Such outside cookies are governed by the privacy policies of the entities placing the ads, and are not subject to this Policy.

We also use a session-based cookie that maintains a user's session for continuity of navigation while viewing the site. After closing the browser the session cookie simply terminates.

With wireless Internet service, cookies are also used by our suppliers and third-party vendors to facilitate the various services and information offered. Depending on the phone or device being used, cookies may be stored locally on the phone or device, or on servers operated by Cingular Wireless. This Internet cookie-like functionality is in place for the same reasons and designed for the same purposes as cookies placed on your computer when interacting with Internet Web sites. Our suppliers and vendors will only use this information to provision the service, but each site you visit while using the wireless Internet service is controlled by a separate company and their individual privacy policies will govern information they receive automatically from the cookie or information you voluntarily provide.

Cingular Wireless Use of Web Beacons

A Web beacon, also known as a Web bug, is a small, graphic image on a Web page, Web-based document or in an email message that is designed to allow the site owner or a third party to monitor the address and other information of the computer viewing the item. Web beacons are often invisible to the user because they are typically very small (only 1-by-1 pixel) and the same color as the background of the Web page, document, or email message. Web beacons are represented as HTML IMG tags in the Web page; users can click on "view profiles" of the Web page to see whether the page is using a Web beacon. Web beacons collect the IP address of the computer that the Web beacon is sent to, the URL of the page the Web beacon comes from, and the time it was viewed. Web beacons can also be linked to personal information.

Cingular Wireless does not place Web beacons that link to personal information on other sites, nor does it permit third parties, other than those working on our behalf, to place them on our site. Cingular Wireless does use Web beacons itself and may link a particular beacon to personal information. For example, we may use a beacon to ensure a user can flip between technical assistance, customer service and our online store and still be recognized as our customer.

Cingular Wireless Placement of Advertising on Other Web Sites Cingular Wireless may use third-party ad serving companies to place advertisements about our products and services on other Web sites. These companies may use cookies and other technology such as Web beacons or tagging to measure the effectiveness of our ads. To measure advertising effectiveness and offer selective ad content, the ad serving companies may use anonymous information about your visits to our and other Web sites. But the ad serving companies use an anonymous number to identify you, NOT your name, address, phone number, email address, or anything that personally identifies you. The use of such cookies is subject to the ad serving company's privacy policy, not the Policy of Cingular Wireless. If you would like more information about these companies we use, their privacy practices, or to learn your choices about not having this non-personal information used to serve ads to you, see our Cingular Wireless Ad Serving Companies.

Cingular Advertising Companies This list contains a link to the privacy policies for the ad-serving companies used to place ads on 3rd party sites. Cingular will revise or update this as we change existing or add new ad-serving companies. [Avenue A and Atlas](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy.aspx).

Presence, Location, and Tracking To make wireless communications possible, the network knows the general location of your phone or wireless device whenever it is turned on. Your wireless device sends out a periodic signal to the nearest radio tower/cell site so that the network will know where to route an incoming communication and how to properly bill for the service. This is necessary to make wireless communications possible.

If you dial 911 for emergency services, we may provide your network location to a public safety answering point, emergency medical service provider or emergency dispatch provider, public safety, fire service, or law enforcement official, or hospital emergency or trauma care facility. The law also permits us to disclose the location of a device on our network without a user's consent (1) to a user's legal guardian or members of a user's immediate family in an emergency situation that involves the risk of death or serious physical harm, (2) to database management services or information providers solely to assist in delivering emergency services, or (3) to a governmental entity if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires or justifies disclosure of a device's location on the network without delay. Legally required upgrades will allow us to provide a location more precise than cell site location. 

In addition, we offer optional services on our GSM/GPRS network that make use of your network location. Please review the terms and conditions for each service for additional information about how the location information will be used. The location used for these services is separate from the network location information when you make a voice call.

Your wireless Internet service may also be personalized using your ZIP code or other location identifiers. We use this information to serve you relevant content, and we treat the information like any other personal information under this Policy. This service does not use the network location technology described in this section.

Receipt of Marketing Messages on My Wireless Device from Third Parties You should be aware that not all advertisements appearing on or delivered to your mobile phone or device are authorized by Cingular Wireless. We have developed and implemented systems in our network to reduce unsolicited bulk short text messages, but we cannot at this time block all such messages. We continue to look for other options to reduce these unsolicited bulk messages. If you have an email account with Cingular Wireless, this service is subject to unsolicited messages as any other email service.

It is unlawful for any third party to make an unsolicited telemarketing call using an autodialer or to send a prerecorded message to a wireless phone or device. You should report any such unsolicited calls to the Federal Communications Commission.

Network and Information Security We maintain a variety of physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to guard your personal information. For example, we use accepted tools and techniques to protect against unauthorized access to our systems. Also, we grant access to personal information about you to employees and contractors who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. In addition, we work to protect the security of your personal information when you are ordering new service via the Cingular Wireless Web site by using well-known Internet encryption technologies like Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). We also use encryption technologies to protect your account information when you are viewing your bill on our Web site. You should be aware that Cingular Wireless has no control over the security of other sites on the Internet you might visit, interact with, or from which you buy products or services.

What Can I Do to Protect My Personal Information? An important part of ensuring the security of personal information is your own effort to protect against unauthorized access to your wireless device and the personal information contained in it and on your SIM card. Most phones and wireless PDA-type devices store calling information both in the phone and on the SIM card. Therefore, before discarding your phone or PDA, trading it in or giving it away, be sure you remove and retain your SIM card and follow the manufacturer's instructions for deleting all personal information on the device itself. (This can be found in your owner's manual or on the manufacturers' Web site.)

In addition, use passwords to prevent unauthorized access to your wireless device, your wireless service account, and your voicemail. If you write down your passwords or user names, keep the information in a secure location. Do not give your password to someone else unless you intend them to have the same full access and ability to make changes to your account as you have. Change your passwords periodically.

Accuracy of Personal Information in Your Account You can review the accuracy of the personal information in your account records online (go to My Account on this Web site) or by contacting Customer Service at 1-800-331-0500.

California customers: Cingular Wireless does not disclose customers' personal information to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes, as governed by California Civil Code 1798.83.

Updating this Policy Cingular Wireless will revise or update this Policy as it deems appropriate, including for example, if our practices change, as we change existing or add new services, as we develop better ways to inform you of products we think will be of interest, or if the law so requires. You should refer back to this page often for the latest information and the effective date of any changes.

If, however, users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify users via posting on this page for 30 days before the material change is made. Users will have a choice as to whether or not their information will be used in this materially different manner.

Contact Us Cingular Wireless is committed to the policies set forth in this Policy. 

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this Policy, please contact [privacy@att.com](mailto:privacy@att.com).

If you have questions about your Cingular Wireless service, you can call a customer service representative at 1-800-331-0500.

Close This Window
